战争要来临了
There is a war coming.
可怕的战争
A-a terrible war.
到时会一片混乱
There-there will be chaos.
街上血流成河
Rivers of blood in the streets.
我知道的
I know it!
我能预见到
I-I can see it coming.
是时候了
It's time.
总得有人接替他  那不如就让我来
Somebody has to take over; it might as well be me.
你好啊  詹姆斯
Hello, James.
老朋友
Old friend.
穆尼  重案组警察
Mooney, the MCU cops--
都不知道企鹅还活着
none of them know Penguin's alive?
他们要是知道  我早死了
If they did, I'd be dead already.
詹姆斯・戈登不是一个好人
James Gordon is not a good guy.
他栽赃马里奥・佩珀为韦恩案的凶手
He framed Mario Pepper for the murder of the Waynes.
詹姆斯・戈登是我见过最正直的人
James Gordon is the most honest man I've ever met.
你这样的好人不适合这座城市和这份工作
This is not a city or a job for nice guys.
你是个愤世嫉俗的人
You're a cynic.
一个吊儿郎当
A slovenly,
懒散又愤世嫉俗的人
lackadaisical cynic.
你也许说对了
You're probably right.
哥谭市  十年前
我是山羊之灵
I am the Spirit of the Goat.
我是山羊
I am the Spirit
之灵
of the Goat.
我是山羊
I am the Spirit...
之灵
of the Goat.
本字幕由 YYeTs 人人影视 原创翻译
[WEB&BD版美剧字幕精编者]再加工制作
本人由衷感谢原译作者的无私奉献  并保留所有译作者的信息
如需其它剧集字幕  请登陆新浪微博（http://weibo.com/MJZM100）
或发邮件索取 lj20090303@163.com
我是山羊之灵
I am the Spirit of the Goat!
哥谭仍处在恐怖笼罩之下
Gotham still held in a grip of terror,
名为"山羊之灵"的神秘蒙面杀手
as the mysterious masked killer known as the Spirit of the Goat
仍逍遥法外
remains on the loose.
但"哥谭山羊"并没有影响到
But Gotham's Goat hasn't cast his shadow
托马斯与玛莎・韦恩爱子的庆生会...
over Thomas and Martha Wayne's celebration of beloved son...
韦恩宅邸向市孤儿院的孩子们敞开了大门
The Wayne family opened their home to the children
与他们共度了欢乐的一天...
of the city orphanage to share in the joyous day with...
雪莉
Shelly.
那是兰道尔・米奇的车
That's the van registered to Randall Milkie.
我们是对的  狄克斯
We were right, Dix.
当然了
Of course we're right.
调度
Dispatch,
我是狄克斯警探
Detective Dix
请求支援  地址是罐头厂街1100号
requesting backup at 1100 Cannery Drive.
走吧  伙计  我们得进去
Come on, man, we gotta get in there.
等等  听我说
Wait a second, listen to me.
等一下
Wait a minute!
听我说
Listen to me.
兰道尔认为他是什么古老的
Randall thinks he's the reincarnation of some
山羊杀手之灵的转世
ancient, murdering goat spirit.
我们必须等后援
We are waiting for backup.
他抓了雪莉・劳森
He's got Shelly Lawson in there.
如果他杀了她
If he kills her,
那我们就有三条人命没从这疯子手上救下了
that's three people we lost to this maniac.
哥谭的金科玉律  哈维
Gotham's Golden Rule, Harvey.
不出英雄
No heroes.
这个混蛋
That son of a bitch.
蠢货  她肯定已经死了
Idiot! She's already dead.
你怎么知道
You don't know that.
我就是知道
Yeah, I know it.
早说了
I told you.
翻译：灰灰是菇凉   艾瑞卡   Reginamoon   哥谭直属   草草
翻译：爵士年代蓬蓬裙   木浅薰   Silence   夜影章鱼X
时间轴：Kallen   宝宝   讷讷       后期：饿得慌
特效：宝宝        校对：草草         总监：草草
雪莉
Shelly.
我就说她肯定已经死了
I told you she'd be cold.
她都在这儿大半个晚上了
She's been here half of the night.
慢着
Wait a minute.
蜡烛是新的  还没怎么熔化
New candles, barely melted.
是刚点上的
Just lit.
好极了
That's great.
太好了
That's great news.
兰道尔・米奇
Randall Milkie?
你被逮捕了
You're under arrest
罪名是杀害雪莉・劳森
for the murders of Shelly Lawson,
丹尼尔・特里蒙特和爱德华・塔伯特
Daniel Tremont and Edward Talbot.
兰道尔  放聪明点  出来
Randall! Be smart, come out of there
不然我们就只能开枪了
or we're gonna have to blow you away!
兰道尔・米奇已经不在了
Randall Milkie is undone.
死了
Gone.
这具肉体的所有者是山羊之灵
This body is moved by the Spirit of the Goat.
还是叫你米奇吧
Uh, we're gonna go with Milkie.
文件我都写好了
I already did the paperwork.
狄克斯
Dix!
你休想阻止山羊之灵
You can never stop the Goat!
即使这具躯体毁灭  我也永不灭
This body may fail, but I will not!
我会回来的  我一定会回来的
I will always come back. I will always come back!
你试试看啊
Come back from this!
米奇
Milkie.
狄克斯
Dix!
醒醒  回答我
Talk to me. Talk to me.
狄克斯  醒醒
Dix, come on, man.
醒醒  狄克斯
Come on. Dix.
-来人啊  -在这里
- Help! - He's through there!
警官负伤
We got an officer down!
急需救治
We need help now!
哥谭
第一季  第六集
哥谭市  如今
布洛克警探
Detective Bullock.
布洛克警探  你放弃了吗
Detective Bullock, do you give up?
-放弃什么  -解开我的谜语
- What? - My riddle.
一个人必须带着
A man has to cross a river
一只狼  一颗白菜和一只山羊过河
with a wolf, a cabbage and a goat...
爱德  说正事
Ed, please.
死亡时间是什么时候
What's the time of death?
验尸官说是今天凌晨3点前
Examiner pegs it at just before 3:00 a.m. this morning.
他对他的凝血指标信心太足
He's a bit eager with his coagulation markers,
要我说大概1点左右
so I'd put it at closer to 1:00.
凶手留下了她的身份证件
Killer left her identification for us.
阿曼达・黑斯廷斯
Amanda Hastings,
21岁
21 years old.
富二代
She comes from money.
我猜她是家中老大
And I'm guessing she was the oldest in her family.
为什么这么说
Why is that?
山羊杀手每次都杀长子女
The Goat always kills the firstborn.
次次如此
It's all the same.
作案手法
The same M.O.,
被害人类型  展示尸体的方式
the same victim choice, presentation...
全都一样  这是模仿犯
it's all the same.We got a copycat.
你还好吧  警探
You all right, Detective?
不  我不好
No, I'm not all right!
我已经破过这个案子了
I already solved this case.
戈登呢
Where's Gordon?
他不接电话
Apparently, he's not answering his phone.
他不接...
He's not answering his...
我比那个模范生到得还早吗
You mean I'm on the clock before the Boy Scout?
太扯淡了
This is freaking ridiculous.
我告诉你答案好了
Fine, I'll tell you the answer.
这个人先带着狼和白菜过河
So the man crosses the river with the wolf and the cabbage.
-把狼留在对岸  然后...  -爱德
- He leaves the wolf, he goes back with... - Ed.
我不会为我的过去道歉
I'm not apologizing for my past.
我没想让你道歉  你没听我说
I'm not asking you to. You're not listening.
不  是你没听我说
No, you're not listening.
我不是想让你撒手不管
I'm not asking you to walk away from this.
是吗  听起来你就是这个意思
Really? Because it sounds like you are.
我们一直这么兜圈子
And we keep going around and around
我反复告诉你我别无选择
and I keep telling you that I don't have a choice.
芭芭拉
Barbara...
这座城市
This city...
这里的法律和罪行
the law, the crime here, they're all...
都像迷宫一样纠缠在一起
twisted up at each other like a maze.
我来这儿是想当警察
I came here to be a cop.
但这城市需要的是别的什么
This city needs something else.
没关系
So, okay...
我理解
I understand.
我只求一样
I'm just asking for one thing:
让我帮你分担一半
half of what you have to carry.
天知道  你已经承担了我的一半包袱
God knows I've... I've dumped my half on you and you carry it.
芭芭拉  我接触的事非常危险
Barbara, what I'm dealing with, it's so dangerous...
只要
Half...
帮你分担一半
of what you carry.
你要是觉得我会怕
If you think I care about the risk,
那你是忘记我是谁了
then you're forgetting who I am.
我发誓我记得
I swear I'm not.
我们没事了吧
Are we okay?
还在吵架吗
Are we still fighting?
我们在谈判
We're negotiating terms.
这对我不利啊
That's not good for me.
你告诉我你在对付谁
You tell me what you're up against.
好吗
Okay?
对我敞开心扉
You let me in.
那我们就没事了
Then we're okay.
-又是工作  -猜就是
- That's work again. - Yep.
我会告诉你全部
I'll tell you everything.
我能告诉的都告诉你  好吗
Everything I can. Okay?
-我会弥补的  -好
- I'll make it right. - Okay.
那里就有一个
There's the one, right there.
我们在河边排查好几天了  蒙托
We've been canvassing this waterfront for days, Monty.
河边流浪汉不会帮我们的
None of these river rats are gonna help us.
24小时内再没线索
We don't get a lead in the next 24 hours,
重案组就要撤案了
MCU is dropping this.
我都残废了6个月了
I'm on the disability six months.
你指望我去哪
Where do you expect me to go?
我们不是要赶你  老家伙
We're not flushing you, old-timer. Okay?
只是想问几个问题
Just want to ask you some questions.
关于前不久发生在那边码头的枪击案
Yeah, about a shooting that took place  recently on that pier back there.
枪击案吗
A shooting?
我看得可清楚了
I saw it good.
好的  太好了  你见过这男人吗
Okay... uh, great. You-you ever this man?
这就是开枪的那个
That was the man did the shooting.
冷血啊  那个男人
A cold customer, that man.
血管里流的是冰
Ice floating in the veins.
我们抓住那个混蛋了
We got the son of a bitch.
我们抓住戈登了
We got Gordon.
"哥谭山羊"
"Gotham Goat"?
是个崇拜者
A wannabe.
作为一个模仿犯  这模仿真是...
For a copycat, the copy is... ugh.
真是超级诡异
Downright creepy, is what it is.
你是接了私活还是怎么的
You moonlighting or something?
我吗
Me?
是啊  因为你迟到了
Yeah. 'Cause you're late
而且看起来萎靡不振的
and you look like crap warmed over.
想的话去打我小报告啊
Write me up if you want.
去你的  模范生
Screw you, Boy Scout.
你心情不错啊
You're in a good mood.
这就是令人反胃的"昨日重现"
I'm in a déjà vu acid flashback.
有人在追杀哥谭的富二代
Someone's hunting the kids of Gotham's top one percent,
媒体肯定得乐疯了
the press will have a field day,
整个城市翻天覆地
city turns upside down,
而整件事都会狠狠地压在哥谭市警局身上
the whole thing's gonna come down on the GCPD like a ton of bricks.
那我们就快点抓到他
Well, then, let's catch him quick.
我认为凶手应该认识死者阿曼达・黑斯廷斯
I'm guessing the killer knew the victim, Amanda Hastings, somehow.
我们去调查一下她家庭
We'll go see the family,
看看能不能找到什么可查的线索
see if we can try to get something we can work with.
还有  尼格玛...
And, Nygma...
他们准备尸检的时候告诉我一声
let me know when they're set up for the autopsy, all right?
要我特别留意什么吗
Anything in particular you want me to look out for?
打给我就是了
Just call me.
你瞧  奇怪的是
You see, the strange thing,
可怕的是
the horrible thing,
我几周以来一直在做一样的梦
is that I've been having the same dream for weeks.
梦见一个黑暗的
Of a dark,
令人喘不过气来的东西
overbearing presence.
黑斯廷斯先生  关于您女儿
Mr. Hastings, about your daughter--
我们知道这很不容易  但是...
and we know that this is difficult-- but...
她生活中有什么人让您觉得担心吗
did she have anyone in her life that worried you?
有什么人会想伤害她吗
Anyone who might have wished her harm?
大家都喜欢阿曼达
Everybody loved my Amanda.
黑斯廷斯先生  您还好吗
Mr. Hastings, are... are you all right?
罗伯特  假如你想休息一会儿
Robert, if you need to take a moment,
应该不会碍事的
I'm sure it'll be all right.
当然了
Absolutely.
来吧
Come on.
我知道二位在争分夺秒地破案
I know you gentlemen are working against the clock,
但恐怕黑斯廷斯先生和夫人
but I'm afraid Mr. And Mrs. Hastings
还没做好这个准备
might not be ready for this.
看得出来
I can see that.
您是黑斯廷斯家的心理医生吗  马科斯医生
And you are the Hastings' family therapist, Dr. Marks?
是的  我主要治疗黑斯廷斯先生
Yes, I treat mostly Mr. Hastings,
但我们也进行多次家庭心理咨询
but we've had many family sessions.
黑斯廷斯先生非常...
Mr. Hastings has a very...
敏感脆弱
delicate nature.
恐怕他完全不能够
I'm afraid he's not at all capable
面对这样的惨剧
of dealing with this kind of tragedy.
没有人能够面对这样的惨剧
No one's capable of dealing with this kind of tragedy.
这就像辆货运火车
It's a freight train.
从你身上碾过去
It runs you over.
你只能尽力捡起残肢断臂
And you try to pick up what's left.
你不相信心理治疗
You don't believe in treatment.
我相信你用来麻痹黑斯廷斯夫人的安定剂
I believe in the tranquilizers you clobbered Mrs. Hastings with.
假如你给我们份样本...
And if you're giving out samples...
行了...
Okay, uh...
警探  也许我们应该...
Detective, maybe we should, uh...
对  你说得对  没错
Yeah, you're right, we should.
失陪了
Excuse me.
谢谢您  医生
Thank you, Doctor.
资料室
好的  明白了
All right, got it...
明白了
and got it.
好的  长官  我马上把那些文件拿过去
Yes, sir, I'll bring those files right away.
尼格玛先生
Mr. Nygma.
你好  柯林格小姐
Hello, Miss Kringle.
我需要你这里所有
So, I'm just looking for all the
关于十年前山羊杀人案的资料
information you have on the Goat Murders from ten years ago.
你不好奇吗
Don't you find it curious?
为什么有人要重演这种老掉牙的怪物杀人谜案
Why someone would resurrect the myth of a centuries-old bogeyman.
而且山羊有什么特别之处
And what is it about the Goat
竟有两个不同的人以它之名杀人
that has made two separate people decide to kill in his name?
我一点都不好奇
No, I-I don't find it curious.
我觉得我会喜欢你父母的
I think I would like your parents.
你说什么
Excuse me?
柯林格  多少见的姓啊
Kringle, such a rare surname.
大多数人会因为觉得丢人
Most people changed it generations ago,
早在几代之前就改换姓氏
out of embarrassment.
你父母不仅保留了这样一个姓
Not only did your parents keep it;
还把你的名字取作  柯丽丝汀
they called you "Kristin."
柯丽丝汀・柯林格
"Kristin Kringle."
他们一定都是幽默感十足的人
They must be very humorous people.
幽默是一种非常重要的品质  你说是吧
Humor is so important, don't you think?
取走任何证据都要记得签字
Remember you have to sign out any evidence you pull.
你这里怎么找东西啊
How do you find anything at all in here?
从组织学的角度讲
I mean, organizationally speaking,
这地方简直一团糟啊
this place is a shambles.
我警告你  尼格玛
I am warning you, Nygma.
这地方我整理得很妥当
I have this exactly as I want it.
我对这里了如指掌
I know where everything is.
明白吗
Understand?
非常明白
Preternaturally.
但...
But...
我可以帮你  柯丽丝汀・柯林格
I can help you, Kristin Kringle.
对此我很是怀疑
I doubt that very much.
这里可以变得更好的
There's a much better way to do this.
阿曼达・黑斯廷斯最后一次出现就是进入这幢大楼
Amanda Hastings was last seen entering this building--
周二的午夜
Tuesday, midnight.
大概是36小时前
That's about 36 hours ago.
你觉得她就是从这里被绑架走的
You think she was abducted from here?
不知道  十年前米奇的作案手法就是这样
I don't know. That was Milkie's M.O. ten years ago.
把被害人分别从家中劫走
He took each one of the victims from their homes.
但犯罪现场调查组没有发现闯入的迹象
But CSI found no signs of a break-in.
当年兰道尔案也是这样
They didn't with Randall, either.
他当时所在的空调维修队
He worked for an air-conditioning maintenance crew
正好负责那三栋大楼
that covered all three buildings.
他有钥匙吗
He had keys?
没错
He had keys.
我是戈登警探
This is Detective Gordon.
给我一份能进入
I need the employee list
黑斯廷斯家大楼的所有维修
of every maintenance and janitorial company
和管理公司的完整职员名单
with access to the Hastings' building.
我会转告他的
Yeah, I'll tell him.
他们准备验尸了
They're ready for the autopsy.
妈妈
Mother!
我等了这么久
I wait for so long,
他总算回来敲门了
and now he scratches at the door,
我的小野猫
the filthy tomcat.
妈妈
Hi, Mom.
我还活着呢
I'm alive.
你为什么总觉得
I don't know why you always think
我是跟什么俗艳的女人跑了
I'm running off with some painted lady.
我都不约会
I don't even date.
那为什么这么久都不给妈妈来个电话
Why you don't call your mother in all this time?
我来说吧
I tell you why.
你就是被什么放荡女人给勾住了
You got tangled in some hussy's demon-purse!
妈妈  没什么女人
Mother, there was no hussy.
只有背叛  暴虐  以及...
Only betrayal and savagery and...
我只是想获得一丝尊重
All I wanted was a little respect.
他们却伤害了我
And they hurt me.
十分残忍
So cruelly.
原来真的没有什么女人
There was no other woman.
我去鬼门关走了一遭  他们想杀了我
I have been to hell and back. They tried to kill me.
又是那些恶霸吗
The bullies again?
我可怜的小心肝啊
My poor, poor darling.
他们这么做都是出于憎恨
They only do these things because they resent you.
嫉妒  厌恶
Envy and spite.
就是这样的
That's all it is.
等着瞧吧  妈妈
You watch, Mom.
我会成为这城里的大人物
I'm gonna be somebody in this town.
我一直都知道
I always knew this.
被害人死于窒息  很可能是乙醚或氯仿
Victim was asphyxiated, likely with ether or chloroform.
检查头皮底下
Look under the scalp.
听我的
Humor me.
在颅底部位
At the base of the skull
应该有个2厘米左右的切口
will be an incision, about an inch long.
缝合好的
Sewn closed.
等等  没错
Wait a minute. Yes.
我居然没注意到
How did I miss that?
有个缝合好的切口
An incision stitched closed,
就在枕骨附近
near the occipital.
里面还缝着异物
Over a foreign object.
什么东西
What is it?
一美分
It's a penny.
他说的没错
He's right.
一美分
A penny?
这是兰道尔・米奇的作案手法
Randall Milkie's M.O.
不可能有人知道这个细节
No one could know that detail.
凶手不是模仿犯
It isn't a copycat.
不可能的
It can't be.
10年前  兰道尔・米奇
Ten years ago, Randall Milkie took
把跟这枚一模一样的1813版美分
an 1813 Liberty penny just like this one
缝进了每个被害人的脑袋里
and sewed it into the heads of each one of his victims.
为什么
Why?
我怎么知道
How the hell do I know?
他袭击了我  脑袋上还带着兽角
He bum-rushed me wearing animal horns.
我打死了他  没来得及聊硬币收藏
I shot him. We didn't talk coin collecting.
你确定没有其他人知道这事
And you're sure no one else could have found this out?
米奇完全就是个独行侠
Milkie was the definition of a loner.
他绝不会告诉别人的
He didn't tell anybody.
我们在报告里也特意略去了这点
We left it out of the file intentionally.
你隐瞒证据
You suppressed evidence.
这叫彩蛋
We "easter-egged" it.
我们认为山羊杀手这样的人
We figured a killer like the Goat would have a good chance
很容易招引崇拜者
of drawing admirers.
没错  这是模仿犯的最爱
Yeah, it's copycat porn.
我们隐瞒了这个细节
We left out this one detail.
硬币的事从未见报
The coins, it never hit the papers.
这只山寨羊到底怎么知道的
How the hell did this copy-Goat know about this?
好吧  就算你隐瞒了此事
Okay, so you hid it.
但验尸官总会知道吧
But the medical examiner, he had to know.
艾德・海耶斯  确实
Ed Hayes. Yeah, sure.
不过他已经死于肝硬化了
But he died of cirrhosis.
所以只剩下我
That just leaves me.
和狄克斯
And Dix.
警监  拜托  他根本没理由...
Captain, please, there's no reason...
去跟他聊聊
Go talk to him.
确保他没和别人提过硬币的事
Make sure he didn't tell anyone about the coins.
干脆问问他有什么想法
Hell, see if he's got any ideas.
我是蕾西・怀特
I'm Lacey White,
欢迎收看哥谭7频道山羊杀手追踪报道
and this is the Gotham 7 Goat Watch.
今夜  哥谭的上流社会将要在模仿犯杀手的
Tonight, Gotham's wealthiest one percent rests fitfully
死亡阴影中战战兢兢了
under a copycat killer's deadly shadow.
如果您恰好是上流社会富贵家族的一员
And if you happen to be one of the city's high-society silver spoons,
那您大概正赶往瑞士阿尔卑斯山避风头呢
then you're probably headed to the Swiss Alps right now...
杀手把大家吓得不轻
They've got them all running like rabbits.
是啊
Yeah.
我不懂他为什么要选个蹄类动物作图腾  但是
I don't know why he chose an ungulate for his totem, but...
他真会吓唬他们
he does know how to scare them, though.
你知道你也是"他们"中的一员吧  布鲁斯少爷
You do realize you happen to be one of "Them," don't you, Master Bruce?
哥谭有钱有势的家庭的长子
Yeah, firstborn son of Gotham's rich and powerful.
也许你该暂时离开这儿
I don't know, maybe you should leave town for a little bit.
去湖边小屋住一段时间
Pop down to the lake house.
你很喜欢那里  不是吗
You like it there, don't you?
我哪也不去
I'm not going anywhere.
我还有事要做
I have work to do.
再说了
Besides...
山羊杀手何必要绑架我呢
why would the Goat take me?
反正这家就剩我一个了
There's no one to take me from.
我的天哪
Oh, my God.
我在升级你的系统
I'm improving your system.
施行根茎式参照索引
Implementing a rhizomatic cross-index,
把你的案卷按主题分类
with your case files classified by subject,
但是排列成类似泥煤苔有机体的生长方式
but arranged more like the way a peat moss organism grows.
就是横向生长
You know, laterally.
这个房间我整理得很好
I had this entire room organized.
是啊  但现在会像根茎一样
Yes, but now it will be rhizomatic.
横向散开
Lateral.
我到底对你做了什么  尼格玛
What did I ever do to you, Nygma?
你为什么非要来这里
What did I do that compels you to come here
没完没了地指手画脚  提建议和出谜语
with your endless notes and suggestions and riddles?
我的天呐  那些谜语
My God, the riddles!
你是想逼我辞职吗
Are you trying to get me to quit?
你不可能想抢我的工作
You can't want my job.
不不不  我要的是你...
No, no, no! I want you.
保住你的工作
To... keep your job
并且好好干  在这里
and to have it. Here.
工作
For working.
我有点觉得
Okay, I'm getting the sense
我的做法似乎不太恰当
that this was somehow inappropriate.
你好奇怪
You are so odd.
我这就把我的非分层数据范式拿走
I'll just take my nonhierarchical data paradigms out of your hair...
让你继续工作
and leave you to your work.
你和这人多久没见过了
How long has it been since you've seen this guy?
布洛克  我知道是怎么回事
Look, Bullock, I know what happened.
任何处在那种情况下的人...
Anybody in your situation...
你以为你能给我当心理医生吗  模范生
Listen, you think you can shrink my head, Boy Scout?
你不能
Because you can't.
我这是黑箱
This is the black box, man.
不能打开  绝对不打开
And we don't open the black box. Ever.
好吧
Okay, fine.
你先去那边坐下
So, why don't you sit your ass down?
我马上就回来
I'll be back in a few minutes.
我们在一起查案
We're both on this case.
狄克斯
Dix.
看看是谁来了
What do we have here?
哈维・布洛克  青年干探
Harvey Bullock, boy detective.
瞧瞧你啊
Look at you up there, huh?
享受着高品质的生活
Living the high life.
瞧瞧我
And me down here,
身体不支  肝脏受损
all broken up with a busted liver.
别把这算我头上  老头子
Don't put that on me, old man.
你受损的肝脏是你的酗酒造成的
Your bum liver's between you and the bottle.
我只是害你断了腿  让你坐上了轮椅
I just busted up your gams and put you in that chair.
哥谭的金科玉律
Gotham's Golden Rule.
不出英雄  布洛克
No heroes, Bullock.
不出英雄
No heroes.
听我说  狄克斯
Listen, Dix.
我们得谈谈那起案子
We have to talk about the case.
山羊杀手
About the Goat.
我还在想你什么时候会来向我求助呢
I was wondering when you were going to come and ask for my help.
我不是来求助的
I'm not asking for your help.
那不代表你不需要
That don't mean you don't need it.
他是什么人
Who's this?
你的搭档吗
Your partner?
我叫詹姆斯・戈登  很高兴认识你
James Gordon. Nice to meet you.
言归正传  狄克斯
Come on, Dix.
你有和任何人提起过兰道尔・米奇吗
You ever tell anyone about Randall Milkie?
那些美分硬币
The Liberty head pennies?
我们说好不提起此事  把事瞒住的
We said we weren't going to. We sealed them.
我当然知道  你个蠢货
I know we sealed them, you jackass!
是我叫你这么做的
I told you to seal them.
但是这个新杀手的作案手法一模一样
Okay, but this new killer's doing the same thing.
他把硬币缝在被害人的脑袋里
He's stitching up coins in the heads of his victims.
知道他是怎么想出来的吗
Any idea how he came up with that?
我没和任何人说过
I didn't tell anybody.
艾德・海耶斯没和任何人说过
Ed Hayes didn't tell nobody.
你也没和任何人说过
And you didn't tell nobody.
那这说明什么
So, what the hell does that mean?
说明我们对米奇的看法是错的
It means we were wrong about Milkie.
他不是单独行动
He was not working alone.
不会
No.
根本没有什么模仿犯
You do not have a copycat killer here.
你们的凶手也不止一人
You do not have a lone killer.
这件案子
What you have...
是个阴谋
is a conspiracy.
把富二代挂在本地古迹上的阴谋吗
A conspiracy to hang rich kids off local historical landmarks?
得了吧
Yeah, right.
他总是觉得自己是最聪明的
He always thinks he's the smartest one in the room.
可不是
I know, right?
那是因为我总是跟白痴待在一起
That's because I'm always in a room full of idiots.
小心点他
Watch out for him.
是吗  为什么
Oh, yeah? Why's that?
他是个我行我素的人
He's a loose cannon.
觉得自己是挺身而出的光明骑士
He thinks he's a white knight jumping into the breach
就像电影里的白痴
like some idiot in the movies.
你是在说布洛克吗
You're talking about Bullock here?
就是在说布洛克
We're talking about Bullock here.
哈维・布洛克
Harvey Bullock?
哈维・布洛克  对
Harvey Bullock, yeah.
布洛克警探  你是想现在就把
Detective Bullock, do you want to settle the bill
这个月的帐结了  还是等我寄给你
for this month now or should we send it to you?
寄过来吧  谢了
You can just put it in the mail, thanks.
他收到我订的那些杂志了吗
Is he getting those magazines I ordered?
那些杂志都很糟糕  警探
Those are awful magazines, Detective.
他拿到了吧
But he's getting them?
是的
Yes. He is.
很好
Good.
谢谢
Thank you.
不  妈妈  我只带了几样东西
No, Mom. I'm just grabbing a few things.
是的  是的  我知道
Yes. Yes, I know.
我9点到码头
I'll be at the marina at 9:00.
好的
Okay.
-给你  -谢谢  安妮塔
- Here you are. - Thank you, Anita.
帮我装些零食好吗
Oh, will you put some snack stuff together, please?
安珀小姐
Miss Ember?
阿妮塔  你见到我的黄丝上衣...
Anita, have you seen the tops to my yellow silk...?
阿妮塔
Anita?
安珀・科普利本该今晚9点和她父母
Ember Copley was supposed to meet her parents tonight
在码头碰面
9:00 at the marina.
她没出现  他们回来发现
When she didn't show, they came back,
女仆昏过去  安珀不见了
found the maid out cold, Ember gone.
你觉得是山羊杀手
You think it's our guy?
没错
It's our guy.
他溜进来  用氯仿麻醉了女仆
He slips in, chloroforms the maid,
拐走了安珀
grabs Ember,
没有强行闯入的痕迹  就像幽灵一样
no sign of B and E, nothing. Like a ghost.
就像他有钥匙一样
Like he had keys.
兰道尔・米奇会举行仪式
Randall Milkie had a ritual.
他会先打扮被害人  然后杀了他们
He'd dress the victims, kill them
再缝硬币  完成这些大概要八小时
and do his little coin trick-- whole thing took about eight hours.
如果山寨羊是按这路数来的话
If our copy-goat's doing the same thing,
我们就快没时间了
we're running out of time.
我调出了安珀・科普利家大楼的
I pulled the employee list from the agencies
维护公司的职员名单
that do maintenance on Ember Copley's building.
正在寻找能进入两名被害人公寓的人
Looking for an employee that had access to both victims' apartments.
那可是不少人啊
That's a hell of a lot of people.
是的  但凶手最近非常忙
Yeah, but our guy's been real busy.
他这几天肯定请病假了
He had to have called in sick the last couple days.
找尼格玛来
Get Nygma in there.
他对谜语异常精通
He's freaky good with puzzles.
好的
You got it.
芮妮  我们得谈谈
Renee, we have to talk.
-你来干什么  -听着  我知道
- What are you doing here? - Look, I know
你认为他做了很可怕的事
you think that he's done terrible things,
但我也知道你在乎事实
but I also know you care about the truth.
你不该来的  芭芭拉  你不该来
You shouldn't be here. Barbara, you shouldn't be seen here.
该死  芮妮  你听我说行不行
Damn it, Renee! Will you listen to me?!
我会和你合作  好吗
Look. I'll work with you, okay?
我会告诉你我知道的一切
I will tell you whatever I know,
我能查明的一切
whatever I can find out.
你不能带有成见  好吗
I need you to keep an open mind, okay?
太晚了
It's too late for that.
不管发生了什么  你都搞错了  芮妮
Whatever's happening, okay, you've got it wrong, Renee.
你不能说  我知道  但不是你想的那样的
You can't tell me, I know that, but it isn't what you think.
他是在保护我
He's trying to protect me.
他不肯告诉我究竟是谁
Okay? He won't tell me who's out there.
-他在害怕谁  -他是对的
- Who he's afraid of. - He's right not to.
等等  为什么
Wait. Why?
因为你会因此送命  好吗
Because it'll get you killed, okay?
你得明白  他知道的事
You understand what he knows,
他认识的人会要了你的命
who he knows will kill you.
我们找了个法官今晚就签发逮捕令
We got a judge issuing a warrant tonight.
芭芭拉  你知道我有多关心你
Barbara, you know how much I care about you.
等戈登被逮捕的时候  你千万要离开那里
When Gordon gets arrested, you have to get out of here.
如果吉姆被捕  那我最该在的地方
If Jim gets arrested, then this is exactly where I have to be.
就是他身边
By his side.
求你了  走吧
Please, just leave.
离开哥谭  直到这一切平息
Get out of Gotham. Just till this is over.
而且别再来找我了
And don't come to me again.
共有四个人从上周起就请了病假
Okay, so four guys have called in sick since last week.
住在外区的两个嫌疑人已经排除了
The two suspects from the outer boroughs are cleared.
还有一人离州了  不过显然还没核实
Another is out of state, but apparently it's unconfirmed.
所以
So...
所以  就剩下一个人了
So... that leaves one last guy.
雷蒙德・厄尔
Raymond Earl.
他的值班长说他最近在一栋建筑里蹭房
His shift supervisor says he's been squatting in a place
在罐头厂公园附近  大概在1100区那边
near Cannery Park, somewhere around the 1100 block.
-就是他  -你确定
- That's him. - You sure?
我确定  我百分百确定
Yeah, I'm sure. I'm 100% sure.
一整天都这么似曾相识
Déjà voodoo all day long.
这就是10年前我们拿下兰道尔・米奇的地方
This is where we got Randall Milkie ten years ago.
狄克斯就是在这里受伤
This is where Dix fell.
布洛克
Bullock.
该进去了
Got to go in.
来吧
Come on.
好  好
Yeah. Yeah.
现在我们将让你永远睡去
We're going to put you to sleep for good now.
能被献祭是你的幸运
You're lucky to be the sacrifice.
去救她
Go get her.
你安全了
You're safe.
你还好吗
You all right?
没事吧
You okay?
你休想阻止山羊之灵
You'll never stop the Goat.
我会回来的
I will always come back.
闭嘴吧你
Quit saying that!
雷蒙德・厄尔  你被捕了
Raymond Earl, you're under arrest.
不赖
Not bad.
很好
All right.
你的西服好了
Your suit is ready.
我熨得平平整整的
I steamed it nice.
多谢了  妈妈
Thanks, Mom.
我真担心你
I'm worried for you.
一脸的心事
So anxious you look.
你做的这些事
These moves you make,
不会惹麻烦吧
they're safe, yes?
你没做什么非法的事吧
You're not doing anything illegal?
没有  妈  别担心
No, Mom. Don't worry.
生意而已
It's just business.
做生意没关系
Well, business is all very fine,
但一定要记住
but always remember...
你谁都不能信
you can trust no one.
只能信妈妈
No one but your mother.
我知道
I know.
但你知道吗
But you know what?
我觉得我总算找到了一个值得信任的人
I think I finally found somebody I can trust.
一个警察
A policeman.
警察
Police?
警察都是骗子
The police are liars.
这个人不是  妈
Hmm-mm, not this one, Mom.
他是个真正的朋友
He's a real friend.
有他帮忙  我会好起来的
He'll help me come out right in the end.
雷蒙德・厄尔  33岁
Raymond Earl, 33 years old,
在市内做门卫
janitor in the city.
他就职的公司为两名被害人所住大楼提供服务
Works with an agency that services the buildings of both victims.
而且他一句话都不说
And he's not talking.
有精神病史
History of mental illness,
曾因为不雅行为  扰乱公共秩序
misdemeanor arrests for lewd and lascivious,
之类的小罪被捕过
public disturbance.
谢天谢地
Thank you, Jesus.
还真被你们逮着了
You got him.
干得漂亮  两位
Good work, detectives.
我有很多电话要去打
I got a lot of phone calls to make.
布洛克  开心点
Bullock, look happier.
怎么了
What?
兰道尔・米奇所工作的维修公司
Randall Milkie worked for a maintenance company
负责被他杀害的人所住的大楼
that serviced the buildings of his victims,
雷蒙德的情况一样
same as Raymond here.
米奇有精神病
Milkie was mentally ill,
无暴力犯罪史
no violent crimes in his history,
他也一样
same as him.
相隔十年  根本不认识
Ten years apart, they never meet,
结果有一天  突然之间
then one day, suddenly, out of the blue,
他们就都决定变成山羊杀手
they both decide to become the Goat?
感觉好像
It's like...
有什么东西找上了他们
it's like something found them.
改变了他们
Changed them.
你是指狄克斯的阴谋论吗
You talking about Dix and his conspiracy theory?
不是
No.
只是觉得不对劲
It just doesn't add up.
而且他怎么知道硬币的事的
And how'd he know about the coin?
我们肯定漏掉了什么
I know that we're missing something,
如果我们不查清楚
and if we keep missing it,
恐怕这事永远没完
I'm afraid we're never gonna stop this.
好吧
Okay.
我们再回去看看米奇的案卷
We go back to Milkie's files.
看看有没有可能的共犯
We, uh... look for possible accomplices,
-任何联系  -明天的吧
- uh, connections... - Tomorrow, tomorrow.
我得想想
I, uh, just... I need... I need to think.
你去...
Why don't you, uh,
休息一下吧
get some rest?
嗯
Yeah.
再见
Night.
再见  吉姆
Good night, Jim.
不  不
No. No.
不
Oh, no.
不  不
No. No.
我了个神啊
Holy Ghost on a bicycle.
芭芭拉
Barbara?
吉姆  听我说
Jim, look.
我并不知道全部  但我知道的够多了
I don't know everything, but I know enough.
你得听我的
You have to listen to me now.
亲爱的  我都站不稳了
Baby, I can barely stand.
蒙托亚有目击证人
Montoya has a witness.
什么
What?
他们坚信你杀了这个科波特
They really believe you killed this Cobblepot person.
-我没有  -现在不重要了
- I didn't. - It doesn't matter anymore.
他们签了一份你的逮捕令
They've got a warrant for your arrest.
你还瞒了我什么
What aren't you telling me?
这几周  你就像变了个人
For weeks now, it's like you've been a different person.
你入职之后不久发生了件什么事
Something happened not long after you started the job.
这件事
Something...
让你无法认同
something you don't feel right about.
他们把我逼进了死角
Somehow, they've cornered me.
让我没有选择
Tied my hands.
跟我走吧
Come with me now. Okay?
我不管我要抛下什么
I don't care what I leave behind,
只要我们能一起走就行
as long as we leave it together.
如果他们带走你  吉姆
If they take you away, Jim,
我怕我会失去你
I'm scared I'll lose you.
-芭芭拉  -求你
- Barbara... - Please!
我不能逃避
I can't run.
不能逃避
Can't run.
詹姆斯・戈登  你因涉嫌杀害
James Gordon... you're under arrest
奥斯瓦尔德・切斯特菲尔德・科波特被捕
for the murder of Oswald Chesterfield Cobblepot.
你有权保持沉默
You have the right to remain silent.
你所说的一切都将作为呈堂证供
Anything you say can be used against you in a court of law.
你在向深处沉沦
You're drifting down and away... deeper...
没事的
I got it.
抱歉打扰你们
I'm sorry to interrupt.
-是布洛克警探吧  -对
- It's Detective Bullock, isn't it? - Yeah.
你是想跟黑斯廷斯先生谈谈吗
Did you want to interview Mr. Hastings?
其实是你的秘书叫我来这儿找你
Actually, your secretary told me I might be able to find you here.
我是想听听你对案子的看法
I was hoping to pick your brain about the case.
我就回来
Oh. Uh, I'll just be a minute.
没事的
It's okay.
我之前没发现
I didn't realize this before.
你是个催眠师  是吧
You're a hypnotist, right?
催眠治疗师
A hypnotherapist.
治疗师
Oh, therapist.
这个词挺有意思
It's a funny word, therapist.
治疗师如果拆开可以念作"强奸犯"
Can either mean "therapist" Or "the rapist," if...
你在一家门诊诊所做免费治疗  是吗
So you do pro bono work at an outpatient clinic?
还是好几家
Or a couple of them?
是的  我想回馈社会
I do. I try to give back.
是啊  你这么做已经挺久的了
Yeah, you've been giving back for a while, uh...
有12年了
12 years now.
真不错
That's good.
老实说
To be honest, I...
我想跟你谈谈你的一位免费病人
wanted to talk to you about one of your pro bono patients.
雷蒙德・厄尔
Uh, Raymond Earl?
他是我们调查中的
He's a person of interest
一位嫌疑人
in our investigation.
记录显示你给他
Our records indicate you've seen him, uh...
治疗过好几次
at least a few times, right?
好像是的
Sounds familiar.
大概是去年吧
Last year, maybe?
黑斯廷斯先生  阿曼达的父亲
And Mr. Hastings, Amanda's father...
他是你的病人
we know he's your patient.
我们昨天来的时候
When we were here yesterday,
他有个奇怪的举动
he was doing something really curious.
就是
It, uh...
他一直不停地握拳
he, uh... he kept clenching his fist.
反反复复
Over and over.
-是啊  他有这习惯  -嗯
- Yes, he does that. - Yeah.
我去查了下资料
See, I was reading about that,
说是如果病人有一种强迫症
and it said that if a patient has a compulsion,
比如有什么坏念头或一种冲动
like a bad idea or an impulse,
催眠师可以把病人催眠
that the hypnotist could put the poor sap under
然后引入一种肢体动作
and introduce a... a physical movement.
比如握拳
Like, uh, clenching your fist.
这样病人受强迫症影响而想做的事就会停止
So instead of doing what the compulsion wants the person to do,
改成只做
they just...
握拳
clench their fist.
就是这个道理  没错
That's how it works, pretty much.
所以黑斯廷斯先生
So Mr. Hastings, when he's in a, uh,
当他面对一屋子人时
room full of people and he wants to start
或许他会想大叫什么的
screaming his head off, I don't know,
但他不会再那么做了  他只会...
instead of doing that, he just...
好的
Okay.
那么雷蒙德・厄尔呢
What about Raymond Earl?
他为什么握拳呢
Why does he clench his fist?
还有兰道尔・米奇呢
And what about Randall Milkie?
我知道你十年多前治疗过他
See, I know you treated him a little over ten years ago,
你可要听好了  接下来的部分有点诡异
and I want you to follow me because this part gets a little weird.
我觉得是有位催眠师把这两个人
See, I think a hypnotist completely turned both those men
彻底颠覆了
upside down.
直到他们抛弃了自己的身份
Until their own identity was the bad idea,
这时候握拳的就不是他们自己了
and then it wasn't even them clenching their fists anymore.
而是山羊之灵
It was the Spirit of the Goat.
我低估了你
I underestimated you.
真的
I really did.
我说对了
So I'm right.
Yes, I'm right.
你去那些门诊诊所到处转
And so you trolled all the outpatient clinics
就为找到兰道尔・米奇这种合适的社会边缘人
so you could find a suitable borderline case like Randall Milkie.
把他催眠  直至那可怜虫
And then you hypnotize the poor bastard
完全忘记了自己的身份
until he literally doesn't even know who he is.
然后我给他灌输新的身份
And then I tell him who he is.
真聪明  警探
That's pretty good intellection, Detective.
为什么
Why?
为什么要催眠一个门卫
Why hypnotize a janitor
把他变成山羊杀手
and turn him into the Goat?
你不会理解的
You wouldn't understand.
说来听听
Try me.
这不是凶杀或疯狂
It isn't an act of murder or madness.
这是治疗
It's an act of therapy.
治疗谁
Therapy? For who?
哥谭
For Gotham.
什么
Excuse me?
这个城市曾经是有希望的
This city used to have hope,
却被他们赶尽杀绝
and they gunned it down in the streets.
那些有钱有势的人
The rich, the powerful.
他们的贪婪是一种病态
Their greed is pathological,
一种疯狂的"本我"  吞噬着哥谭
an id run rampant, eating Gotham alive.
所以你的解决方案就是杀光市里的富二代
So your one-percent solution is to kill the city's rich kids?
负强化
Negative reinforcement.
相信山羊杀手真实存在
To believe that the Goat is real,
相信它不会忍受现状
that it wouldn't tolerate this...
这是哥谭需要的
Gotham wanted that.
不管这多么痛苦
No matter how painful it was.
有句话说得对
It's true what they say.
你能催眠一个人去做的事
You can't really hypnotize somebody to do something that,
都是他们内心深处其实早就想做的事
deep down, they don't already want to do.
内心深处
And deep down,
我们都仇富
we all want to eat the rich.
是不是
Don't we?
你是个百分百的疯婆子
You are 100% nuthouse crazy, lady.
马科斯医生  没事吧
Dr. Marks... is everything okay?
有事
No, it's not.
马科斯医生  你被捕了
Dr. Marks, you're under arrest
罪名是阴谋谋杀  强迫
for conspiracy to commit murder, coercion
老实说  估计有几项罪名
and, frankly, a few things
我们得以你来命名了
we're probably gonna have to name after you.
我还留了一手给你呢
Well, I do have another one for you.
罗伯特  黄金庙宇开放了
Robert, the golden temple is open.
杀了这个人
Now kill this man.
罗伯特
Robert...
醒醒  黑斯廷斯先生
Heel, Mr. Hastings! Heel!
别动  女人
Freeze, lady!
再说一遍
One more time.
再跟我说一遍
Take me through the part
你开车去上城区
where you drove to the nice part of town
开枪射伤一位女医生的部分
and shot the doctor lady.
我们抓到另一部分凶手了
We caught the other half of the killer.
马科斯医生就是山羊之灵
Dr. Marks was the Spirit of the Goat.
-你瞧  这就是我不...  -...是一边的
- Okay, see, that's the part that I don't... - ...on the same side,
-理解的部分  -明白吗
- get. - do you understand?
我们在打同一场仗
We're fighting the same war,
而且我已经有进展了
and damn it, I'm getting somewhere.
你要进的是6乘8的黑门监狱囚室
Getting into a six-by-eight in the Blackgate Pen,
没别的了
that's what you're getting.
怎么回事
What is this?
重案组今天要逮捕詹姆斯・戈登警探
MCU's taking Detective James Gordon into custody.
-什么  -你的警探杀了
- What? - Your boy here murdered
奥斯瓦尔德・科波特并把他弃尸河中
Oswald Cobblepot and dumped him in the river.
撒谎
That's a damn lie!
他说得对  那是个谎言
He's right. It was a lie.
我没杀奥斯瓦尔德・科波特
I didn't shoot Oswald Cobblepot.
我撒谎了  我没杀他  布洛克
I lied. I didn't shoot him, Bullock.
当然了  搭档
Of course you didn't, partner.
我说真的
No, I mean it!
哈维・布洛克  你也被捕了
Harvey Bullock, you're under arrest.
为什么
For what?
你是奥斯瓦尔德・科波特被杀一案中的从犯
Accomplice in the murder of Oswald Cobblepot.
我们有目击证人证明你在场
Our witness places you at the scene.
你以为你就能这么冲进来抓走我的人吗
You think you can walk in here and take my people like that?
我们不是来扳倒整个哥谭市警局的
We're not here to take down the GCPD.
我们只要他们俩
We just want these two.
他们就是哥谭市警局的
Well, they're GCPD,
所以重案组要有麻烦了
so the MCU's got a problem.
是啊  你有麻烦了  你们麻烦大了
Yeah, you got a problem. You got a real problem, you...
我去
Holy crap.
你们好
Hello.
我是奥斯瓦尔德・科波特
I am Oswald Cobblepot.
你个小混蛋
You son of a bitch.
-哈维  -你个混蛋
- Harvey... - You son of a bitch!
如需其它字幕  请登陆新浪微博[WEB&BD版美剧字幕精编者]
或发邮件 lj20090303@163.com